Montgomery C. Meigs Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Montgomery C. Meigs Papers 1799-1971 1849-1892
MSS32540
Meigs, Montgomery C. (Montgomery Cunningham), 1816-1892
11,000 items
52 containers plus 10 oversize
27 linear feet
51 microfilm reels
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Army officer, engineer, architect, and scientist. Correspondence, diaries and journals, notebooks, family papers, military papers, drawings and plans, scrapbooks, and other papers relating primarily to Meigs's work in the United States Army Corps of Engineers, his service as quartermaster general during the Civil War, and family matters.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887--Correspondence.; Buchanan, James, 1791-1868--Correspondence.; Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 1824-1881--Correspondence.; Bülow, Bernhard Ernst von, 1815-1879--Correspondence.; Cameron, Simon, 1799-1889--Correspondence.; Cluss, Adolph, 1825-1905--Correspondence.; Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889--Correspondence.; Floyd, John B. (John Buchanan), 1806-1863--Correspondence.; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872--Correspondence.; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878--Correspondence.; Holt, Joseph, 1807-1894--Correspondence.; Manning, Charles P.--Correspondence.; McClellan, George B. (George Brinton), 1826-1885--Correspondence.; Meigs, Charles D. (Charles Delucena), 1792-1869--Correspondence.; Meigs, Emlen--Correspondence.; Meigs, John Rodgers, 1842-1864.; Meigs, Louisa Rodgers--Correspondence.; Meigs, Montgomery C. (Montgomery Cunningham), 1816-1892.; Meigs, Montgomery, 1847-1931. Montgomery Meigs papers.; Moltke, Helmuth, Graf von, 1800-1891--Correspondence.; Porter, David D. (David Dixon), 1813-1891--Correspondence.; Seward, Frederick William, 1830-1915--Correspondence.; Seward, William H. (William Henry), 1801-1872--Correspondence.; Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891--Correspondence.; Stanton, Edwin M. (Edwin McMasters), 1814-1869--Correspondence.; Totten, Joseph Gilbert, 1788-1864--Correspondence.
Organizations
United States Capitol (Washington, D.C.); United States. Army. Corps of Engineers.; United States. Army. Quartermaster's Department.; United States. Pension Bureau--Buildings.
Subjects
Aqueducts--Maryland.; Aqueducts--Washington (D.C.); Architecture--Washington (D.C.); Public buildings--Washington (D.C.)
Places
Europe--Description and travel.; Texas--Description and travel.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Washington (D.C.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Washington Aqueduct (Md. and Washington, D.C.)
Titles
Montgomery C. Meigs Papers at the Library of Congress
Occupations
Architects.; Army officers.; Engineers.; Scientists.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Montgomery C. Meigs, army officer, engineer, architect, and scientist, were given to the Library of Congress by his descendants from 1920 to 1986. A large addition was purchased in 1982, and other items were obtained by transfer and purchase between 1976 and 2001.
Transfers
Some photographs have been transferred to the Library's Prints and Photographs Division where they are identified as part of these papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Montgomery C. Meigs are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Microfilm
A microfilm edition of part of these papers is available on two sets of microfilm with a total of fifty-one reels. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division concerning availability for purchase or interlibrary loan. To promote preservation of the originals, researchers are required to consult the microfilm edition.
Online Content
The papers of Montgomery C. Meigs are available on the Library of Congress Web site at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/collmss.ms000104. To promote preservation of the originals, researchers are required to consult the online edition as available.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1816, May 3 Born, Augusta, Ga.
1832 Entered United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y.
1837 Second lieutenant, Corps of Engineers Surveyed Upper Mississippi River
1838 Survey engineering work, Delaware River
1839 Duty at army headquarters, Washington, D.C.
1841 Married Louisa Rodgers (died 1879)
1843 1852 Stationed in Detroit, Mich., until return to permanent duty in Washington, D.C.
1852 Supervised construction of the Washington aqueduct for Great Falls, Va., and various United States Capitol improvements, including a new and larger dome
1861, June Appointed quartermaster general, United States Army
1865, Apr. 15 Present at the death of Abraham Lincoln
1867 Postwar illness and trip to Europe
1882 Retired from the United States Army Began engineering work on the Pension Office building, Washington, D.C.
1892, Jan. 2 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Montgomery Cunningham Meigs (1816-1892) span the years 1799-1971, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1849-1892. The collection consists of diaries, journals and notebooks, family papers, correspondence, drawings, maps and plans, photographs, scrapbooks, sketches and studies, and miscellaneous documents. The papers are organized in seven series: Diaries, Journals, and Notebooks; Family Papers; Correspondence, Military Orders, and Related Matter; Miscellany; Addition I; Addition II; and Oversize.
Meigs was a career army officer who graduated from the United States Military Academy in 1836. After a brief stint in an artillery unit, he was transferred to the Corps of Engineers, where he directed engineering projects for the United States Army between 1852 and 1882. Among the building programs Meigs supervised were the Washington, D.C., aqueduct and its masonry arch at Cabin John, the wings and dome of the national Capitol, an addition to the General Post Office building, a post-Civil War extension of the aqueduct, and from 1882 to 1892 after his retirement from the army, the Pension Office building. Lincoln put Meigs in charge of secret plans for the aid of Fort Pickens, Florida, immediately before the outbreak of the Civil War and in June 1861 appointed him quartermaster general of the army. Meigs supplied the Union forces throughout the war and supervised the construction of at least four major federal buildings. In 1875 he visited Europe to study the organization and command of continental armies.
The papers in this collection consist mostly of private entry books and personal correspondence. Although some material relates to the fighting during the Civil War, the bulk of the papers deals with the construction of federal buildings in Washington. Meigs's journals contain detailed notes in mid-nineteenth century shorthand on the planning for the aqueduct as well as the expansion of the Capitol and the erection of the Pension Office building. Interspersed throughout the journals and sketchbooks are clippings, photographs, and architectural drawings of major buildings under various stages of construction. The combination of written and illustrative material provides a rich source for the study of nineteenth-century Washington and its architecture.
The Family Papers contain correspondence and printed items from Meigs's immediate relatives and descendants. The major portion, however, comprises his letters to his father, Charles D. Meigs, his brother, Emlen, and his wife, Louisa Rodgers Meigs. The letters to his father, a Philadelphia surgeon and medical editor, are concentrated in the Civil War period; those to his wife and other family members are focused on Meigs's trip to Europe in 1875.
Correspondents in the Meigs Papers include Spencer Fullerton Baird, James Buchanan, Bernhard Ernst von Bülow, Adolf Cluss, Jefferson Davis, Charles P. Manning, Graf Helmuth von Moltke, David D. Porter, Frederick William Seward, William T. Sherman, and Joseph Gilbert Totten. The letterbook, much of which is illegible or undecipherable, contains copies of outgoing letters to family members as well as friends and associates and also includes numerous drawings. The volume for April 1861-February 1862 pertains exclusively to the Civil War, while later volumes focus principally on architectural projects.
Addition I
Addition I of the Meigs Papers parallels the earlier portion in scope, arrangement, and content. There are unbound diary entries, a commonplace book from Meigs's first years in the military, and an illustrated journal which he kept during a trip to Texas, 1869-1870. The Family Papers, the dominant feature of Addition I, include letters between his wife, Louisa Rodgers Meigs, and Rodgers family members and correspondence between Montgomery Meigs, his wife and family members, and other relatives. Especially notable in the Family Papers is a sequence of personal and official communications regarding the killing of Meigs's eldest son, John Rodgers Meigs, by Confederate guerrillas in 1864. Meigs believed that his son was the victim of a cold-blooded murder, possibly because of his status as the son of the Union quartermaster general. John Rodgers Meigs had been heralded for his bravery during early battles of the Civil War, and his hand-drawn map of the First Battle of Bull Run and other Civil War documents and correspondence amplify other material in the collection from that period. Also prominent in Addition I are letters, documents, sketches, drawings, and other designs relating to Montgomery Meigs's work on construction of the Capitol, the Washington Aqueduct, and other Army Corps of Engineers projects. Noteworthy as well are correspondence and career papers pertaining specifically to the younger Montgomery Meigs (1847-1931), who followed in his father's footsteps as a public works engineer.
Correspondents include family members Charles D. Meigs and Samuel Emlen Meigs (who often used his middle rather than first name or first initial) and prominent individuals such as Ambrose Everett Burnside, Simon Cameron, Jefferson Davis, John B. Floyd, Horace Greeley, Joseph Henry, Joseph Holt, George Brinton McClellan, William Henry Seward, and Edwin MacMasters Stanton.
Addition II
Addition II includes a Book of Common Prayer inscribed by Meigs and carried by him to Fort Pickens at the start of the Civil War; a handwritten letter of 1879 concerning personal matters; and photocopies of two typewritten letters, dated 1891, to his daughter, Louisa Meigs Forbes. Also in Addition II are photocopies and typed transcripts of a poem written by John Rodgers Meigs, presumably while a cadet at the United States Military Academy between 1859 and 1863, and six volumes of the translated text of Meigs's shorthand journals, 1853-1859, 1861, as well as an index to the journals.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in ten series:
Diaries, Journals, and Notebooks, 1850-1891
Family Papers, 1850-1968
Correspondence, Military Orders, and Related Matter, 1853-1892
Miscellany, 1849-1960
Addition I: Diaries, Journals, and Commonplace Book, 1836-1888
Addition I: Family Papers, 1799-1967
Addition I: Correspondence, Military Orders, and Related Matter, 1836-1890
Addition I: Miscellany, 1815-1971
Addition II: Miscellany, 1845-1891
Oversize, 1835-1885
Container List
- Diaries, Journals, and Notebooks, 1850-1891 (Box 1-12, Reel 1-15*)
  Pocket diaries, bound diaries, unbound diary entry sheets, extracts of diaries, and memoranda notebooks and journals with writings, notations, photographs, and drawings. The journals are largely in shorthand.
  Arranged by type of material and therein chronologically.
  *Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 18,202
  - Diaries (Box 1, Reel 1*)
    - Pocket
      - 1850
      - 1853
      - 1855
      - 1856
      - 1857
      - 1858
      - 1859
      - 1860 (Box 1, Reel 2*)
      - 1861
      - 1862
      - 1863
      - 1864
      - 1865 (Box 2, Reel 3*)
      - 1865
      - 1866
      - 1867
      - 1868
      - 1869
      - 1870 (Box 2, Reel 4*)
      - 1871
      - 1872
    - Bound (Box 3, Reel 4*)
      - 1867-1868
      - 1869-1870 (Box 3, Reel 6*)
      - 1868, 1870-1871 (Box 3, Reel 5*)
      - 1872-1875 (Box 3, Reel 9*)
      - 1875-1876 (Box 4, Reel 7*)
      - 1877-1878
      - 1877-1878 (cont.) (Reel 8a*)
      - 1879 (Box 4, Reel 8*)
      - 1879-1880 (Box 5, Reel 10*)
      - 1881
      - 1882 (Box 6, Reel 10*)
      - 1883 (Box 6, Reel 11*)
      - 1884 (Box 7, Reel 11*)
      - 1885
      - 1886
      - 1887 (Box 8, Reel 12*)
    - Unbound
      - 1874 (typed by Meigs; includes copies of letters sent)
    - Extracts, 1860-1865
  - Notebooks, 1863-1866
    - 1 of 6
    - 2 of 6
    - 3 of 6
    - 4 of 6
    - 5 of 6
    - 6 of 6
  - Journals (Box 9, Reel 13*)
    - 1852-1855
    - 1856-1857 See also Oversize (Box 10, Reel 13*)
    - 1857-1860 (Box 11, Reel 14*)
    - 1860-1872 See also Oversize (Box 12, Reel 15*)
- Family Papers, 1850-1968 (Box 13-15, Reel 16-17*)
  Correspondence, diaries, clippings, printed matter, reminiscences, wills, obituaries, and related matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of family member and therein by type of material.
  - Alger, Mrs. Philip Rounseville (granddaughter), 1934-1963 (Box 13, Reel 16*)
  - Meigs, John Rodgers (son), 1858-1895
  - Meigs, Montgomery C. (1816-1892)
    - Correspondence
      - Meigs, Charles Delucena (father)
        - 1863
        - 1864, July-Dec.
        - 1865, Aug.-Oct.
        - 1865, Nov.-1866, Jan.
        - 1866, Feb.-May
      - Others
        - 1863-1871
        - 1872-1874
        - 1875-1888, undated
    - Will and obituaries, 1885-1892 (Box 14, Reel 16*)
  - Meigs, Louisa Rodgers (wife), travel diary, 1875
  - Rodgers, John (brother-in-law), 1864-1882
  - Taylor, John R. M., 1920
  - Taylor, Joseph Hancock (son-in-law), 1850-1887
  - Taylor, Mary Meigs (daughter), 1886-1968 (Box 15, Reel 17*)
  - Miscellaneous, 1883-1911
- Correspondence, Military Orders, and Related Matter, 1853-1892 (Box 15-18, Reel 17-23*)
  Correspondence sent and received, with related printed matter, army decrees, and memoranda and copies of bound outgoing correspondence by Meigs.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - General See also Oversize (Box 15, Reel 17*)
    - 1853-1870
    - 1871-1875
    - 1876-1882
    - 1883-1892, undated
  - Letterbooks (Box 15, Reel 17*)
    - 1857, May-1858, Sept.
    - 1860, Mar.-1861, Mar. (Box 16, Reel 18*)
    - 1858, Sept.-1859, Aug. (Box 16, Reel 19*)
    - 1859, Aug.-1860, Mar.
    - 1861, Apr.-1862, Feb. (Box 17, Reel 20*)
    - 1864, Apr.
    - 1879, May-Oct.
    - 1882, Mar.-Oct. (Box 18, Reel 21*)
    - 1882, Oct.-1883, Mar. (Box 18, Reel 22*)
    - 1885-1887 (Box 18, Reel 23*)
- Miscellany, 1849-1960 (Box 19-25, Reel 23-27*)
  Account books, financial matter, drawings, maps, photographs, printed matter, reminiscences, scrapbooks, miscellaneous notes and writings, and sketches.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Account books (Box 19, Reel 23*)
    - 1849-1851 See also Oversize
    - 1852-1863
    - 1853-1880 (Box 19, Reel 24*)
    - 1886-1891 (1 of 2)
    - 1886-1891 (2 of 2)
    - 1892-1908
    - Account materials (loose)
  - Drawings (Box 20, Reel 24*)
    - 1850-1853, (2 folders)
    - 1859-1860
    - 1868, (3 folders)
    - 1872-1873 See also Oversize (Box 21, Reel 25*)
    - 1875-1876
    - 1876-1877
    - 1877-1892
  - Maps, 1864, 1882, 1889, undated See Oversize (Box 22, Reel 25*)
  - Photographs
    - Albums
      - Public buildings, 1859-1861, undated
      - Washington Aqueduct, Washington, D.C., 1859-1864
      - Miscellany, 1859-1860, undated (Box 23, Reel 25*)
    - Loose items, family, 1859-1864, 1924, undated
  - Printed matter (Box 23, Reel 26*)
    - Cards and passes, 1856-1867, undated
    - Clippings (Box 24, Reel 26*)
      - Miscellaneous, 1856-1926, undated (1 of 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 1856-1926, undated (2 of 2)
      - Taylor family, 1926, 1949, undated
    - Pamphlets, 1866-1896, 1960, undated
  - Reminiscences and outlines, 1861-1888
  - Scrapbooks
    - Pension Office building, Washington, D.C., 1882-1891 See also Oversize
    - War miscellany, 1861-1862, undated See also Oversize
  - Scraps and notes, 1864-1889, 1914, undated
  - Sketches, 1856-1882 See also Oversize (Box 25, Reel 27*)
- Addition I: Diaries, Journals, and Commonplace Book, 1836-1888 (Box 26, Reel 1**)
  Unbound diary entries, a journal of a trip to Texas, 1867, consisting of letters sent by Meigs and sketches he compiled, and a commonplace book containing what may be the key to his shorthand code.
  Arranged by type of material.
  **Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 18,202.1
  - Commonplace book, 1836-1844 (Box 26, Reel 1**)
    - Part I
    - Part II
  - Diaries, unbound, 1888
  - Journal, trip to Texas and back, 1869-1870
    - Part I
    - Part II
- Addition I: Family Papers, 1799-1967 (Box 26-38, Reel 1-11**)
  Correspondence between family members, with additional items such as wills, school papers, military reports, and reminiscences.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person and therein by type of material. The correspondence is organized in chronological order.
  - Forbes, Louisa Meigs (daughter) (Box 26, Reel 1**)
    - Correspondence, 1876
    - School papers, 1862-1863
  - Macomb, J. N. (brother-in-law), 1862, 1870
  - Meigs, Charles Delucena
    - Correspondence
      - Biddle, Emily Meigs (sister), 1835
      - Meigs, Henry (brother), 1860-1866
      - Meigs, John Rodgers, 1850-1863
      - Meigs, Mary Montgomery (mother), 1817-1842
      - Meigs, Montgomery (son) (1847-1931), 1867-1868 (Box 27, Reel 1**)
      - Meigs, Samuel Emlen (brother), 1855
      - Others, 1861-1867
    - Funeral, 1869
  - Meigs, Clara (grandmother), 1836
  - Meigs, Cornelia (granddaughter), 1957-1967
  - Meigs, John Rodgers (son)
    - Correspondence
      - Forbes, Louisa Meigs, 1862, undated
      - Hart, Mary Meigs (sister), 1859-1861, undated
      - Macomb, Nannie Rodgers (sister-in-law), 1859, undated
      - Meigs, Frank B. (brother), 1860-1861
      - Meigs, Mary Montgomery, 1861
      - Meigs, Montgomery (1847-1931), 1859-1862, undated, (3 folders)
      - Taylor, Mary Meigs
        - 1859-1860
        - 1861-1862
        - Undated
      - Others, 1859-1864, undated (Box 27, Reel 2**)
    - Other papers
      - In memory of John Rogers Meigs by Louisa R. Meigs, 1864
      - Military record and biographical data
      - Report on First Battle of Bull Run, Va., 1861 See also Oversize
      - United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y., 1860-1863
  - Meigs, Louisa Rodgers
    - Correspondence
      - Biddle, Emily Meigs, 1853-1870
      - Forbes, Louisa Meigs, 1866, 1876
      - Hart, Mary Meigs, 1863-1877
      - Macomb, Nannie Rodgers, 1851-1877 (Box 28, Reel 2**)
      - Meigs, Charles D. and Mary Montgomery, 1859-1868, undated
      - Meigs, John Forsyth and Anne Ingersoll (brother and sister-in-law), 1852-1859
      - Meigs, John Rodgers
        - 1859-1864
        - Undated
      - Meigs, Montgomery (1847-1931)
        - 1860-1867
        - 1868-1874
        - Undated (Box 28, Reel 3**)
      - Rodgers, Minerva, 1850-1874, undated
      - Rodgers, Robert Smith and Sara (brother-in-law and sister-in-law), 1853-1870
      - Taylor, Mary Meigs (Box 29, Reel 3**)
        - 1858-1869
        - 1868-1874
        - 1875-1877
      - Others
        - Family, 1828-1876
        - Non-family, 1852-1876, undated
    - Will, 1851, 1870-1880
  - Meigs, Mary Montgomery, correspondence
    - Meigs, Henry, 1861
    - Meigs, William M. (brother), 1854
  - Meigs, Montgomery C. (1816-1892)
    - Correspondence
      - Biddle, Emily Meigs, 1853-1869
      - Forbes, Louisa Meigs, 1860-1891
      - Hart, Mary Meigs, 1861-1869
      - Macomb, Nannie Rodgers and John Navarre, 1850-1888
      - Meigs, Anne Ingersoll (sister-in-law), 1853-1855 (Box 29, Reel 4**)
      - Meigs, Charles D. (brother), 1837-1871
      - Meigs, Charles Delucena
        - 1840-1852
        - 1853
        - 1854 (Box 30, Reel 4**)
        - 1855-1856
        - 1857
        - 1858
        - 1859
        - 1860 (Box 30, Reel 5**)
        - 1861 See also Oversize (Box 31, Reel 5**)
        - 1862
        - 1863
        - 1864, Jan.-June
        - 1864, July-Dec. (Box 31, Reel 6**)
        - 1865
        - 1866 (Box 32, Reel 6**)
        - 1867
        - 1868
        - 1869, undated
      - Meigs, Frank B., 1849-1869
      - Meigs, Henry, 1850-1867
      - Meigs, John Forsyth (Box 32, Reel 7**)
        - 1839-1861
        - 1862-1876, undated
      - Meigs, John Rodgers (Box 33, Reel 7**)
        - In code, 1855-1863 (organized by year only)
        - In longhand, 1859-1864
      - Meigs, Louisa Rodgers
        - 1852-1853
        - 1854-1857
        - 1858-1860
        - 1861
        - 1862 (Box 33, Reel 8**)
        - 1863, Jan.-Oct. (Box 34, Reel 8**)
        - 1863, Nov.-Dec., undated
        - 1864
        - 1865-1869
        - 1870-1873
        - 1874-1876
        - Undated
      - Meigs, Mary Montgomery, 1849-1867
      - Meigs, Montgomery (1847-1931)
        - In code, 1866-1867 (organized by year only)
        - In longhand (Box 34, Reel 9**)
          - 1854-1868
          - 1868-1891, undated
      - Meigs, Samuel Emlen, 1856-1888, undated (Box 35, Reel 9**)
      - Rodgers, Augustus F. (brother-in-law), 1855-1856
      - Rodgers, Christopher R. Perry (cousin), 1860-1876
      - Rodgers, John, 1861-1869
      - Rodgers, John F. (son of Christopher R. P. Rogers), 1862-1867
      - Rodgers, Minerva Denison, 1855, 1867
      - Rodgers, Robert Smith (brother-in-law), 1853-1867
      - Rodgers, William Pinkney (brother-in-law), 1855-1876
      - Taylor, Mary Meigs and Joseph Hancock, 1852-1876, undated
      - Other relatives, 1854-1876
    - Will, 1867-1892
  - Meigs, Montgomery (1847-1931)
    - Correspondence
      - Biddle, Christine, 1867-1868, undated
      - Forbes, Louisa Meigs, 1863-1873, undated
      - Hart, Mary Meigs, 1867-1868
      - Macomb, Nannie Rodgers, 1865-1876
      - Meigs, Cornelia, 1927
      - Taylor, Mary Meigs, 1867-1868
      - Other
        - Family, 1868-1900
        - Letterbook, 1876, Nov.-1896, Aug. (Box 36, Reel 10**)
        - Non-family, 1866-1890, undated (Box 37, Reel 10**)
    - Other papers
      - Confirmation certificate, 1864
      - Lecture book from Stuttgart Polytechnic, Stuttgart, Germany
        - 1867-1868 See also Oversize
        - 1871 (Box 38, Reel 11**)
      - Notebook/scrapbook, 1867-1879
      - Paper on mathematics, 1864
      - School papers, 1861-1863, undated
      - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1879, undated
  - Meigs, Samuel Emlen, personal recollections, 1900
  - Taylor, Mary Meigs, correspondence
    - Macomb, Nannie Rodgers, 1867
    - Others, 1861, undated
  - Rodgers, John (father-in-law), 1799-1834
  - Rodgers, Minerva Denison, will and real estate, 1875, 1883
  - Miscellany
    - Fragments and unidentified, 1861, 1873, undated
    - Genealogical lists and data, 1959, undated
- Addition I: Correspondence, Military Orders, and Related Matter, 1836-1890 (Box 38-47, Reel 11-20**)
  Correspondence sent and received by Meigs with related printed matter, military orders and decrees, financial data, and official memoranda. The material is divided into a general file of papers sent and received and a letterbook file containing only copies of letters sent by Meigs.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - General (Box 38, Reel 11**)
    - 1836-1854
    - 1855-1856
    - 1857 (Box 39, Reel 11**)
    - 1858
    - 1859 (Box 39, Reel 12**)
    - 1860
    - 1861, Jan.-Apr.
    - 1861, May-June
    - 1861, July-Dec.
    - 1862, Jan.-July (Box 40, Reel 12**)
    - 1862, Aug.-Dec.
    - 1863, (2 folders)